<texts>
    <text>
        Closed captions were created for deaf or hard of hearing individuals to assist in comprehension. They can also be used as a tool by those learning to read, learning to speak a non-native
        language, or in an environment where the audio is difficult to hear or is intentionally muted.
    </text>
    <text>
        Today, historians relate that , as a general rule, buying and selling securities was very much unorganized before the year 1792. Every person who owned a security faced the problem of finding interested buyers who might consider the purchase of a debt-free investment. This meant most people were somewhat slow in investing in stocks and bonds because these securities could not readily be converted into money. We have been told that an interesting number of traders and merchants agreed to try to do something to help correct the situation. At this first crucial meeting, they decided that it was a good idea to visit regularly on a daily basis to buy and sell securities. The group of leaders, whose meeting place was under an old, tall cottonwood tree, found the needed time to plot the financial future of our nation. We know from reading the old records that the original team who met together long ago in May became the very first members of the New York Stock Exchange. The New York Stock Exchange is still operating. Other stock exchanges conduct business in many countries around the world. Thousands and thousands of stocks and bonds are bought and sold each day.
    </text>
    <text>
        One morning my friend and I were thinking about how we could plan our summer break away from school. Driving from our own state to several nearby states would help to expand our limited funds. Inviting six other friends to accompany us would lower our car expenses. Stopping at certain sites would also help us stretch our truly limited travel budget. Yesterday I engaged in an interesting and enlightening discussion about finances. I found it difficult to imagine that during my lifetime I might well earn at least one-half million dollars. It is also possible that I might spend as much as one-half million during the same period. The really difficult thing for me to do will be to save more of the half-million than I spend. Thinking about today's high cost of living makes this seem an impossible task for most. Last week I asked a friend to talk with me and a girl-friend about college. Our friend is the Dean of Women at a nearby college. The Dean and her staff spend much of their time talking to students who plan to go to college. The first thing she said was to work very hard each day in high school. Good grades are most important for being accepted. Being on time for classes and having a good view toward all phases of the school life are two other things to remember.
    </text>
    <text>
        Word processors evolved dramatically once they became software programs rather than dedicated machines. They can usefully be distinguished from text editors, the category of software they evolved from. Word processing added to the text editor the ability to control type style and size, to manage lines (word wrap), to format documents into pages, and to number pages. Functions now taken for granted were added incrementally, sometimes by purchase of independent providers of add-on programs. Spell checking, grammar checking and mail merge were some of the most popular add-ons for early word processors. Word processors are also capable of hyphenation, and the management and correct positioning of footnotes and endnotes. Later desktop publishing programs were specifically designed with elaborate pre-formatted layouts for publication, offering only limited options for changing the layout, while allowing users to import text that was written using a text editor or word processor, or type the text in themselves.
    </text>
    <text>
        Because of the laboriousness of the translation process, since the 1940s efforts have been made, with varying degrees of success, to automate translation or to mechanically aid the human translator. More recently, the rise of the Internet has fostered a world-wide market for translation services and has facilitated "language localization". Ideally, the translator must know both languages, as well as the subject that is to be translated.
    </text>
    <text>
        Many touch typists also use keyboard shortcuts or hotkeys when typing on a computer. This allows them to edit their document without having to take their hands off the keyboard to use a mouse. An example of a keyboard shortcut is pressing the Ctrl key plus the S key to save a document as they type, or the Ctrl key plus the Z key to undo a mistake. Many experienced typists can feel or sense when they have made an error and can hit the Backspace key and make the correction with no increase in time between keystrokes.
    </text>
    <text>
        A late 20th century trend in typing, primarily used with devices with small keyboards (such as PDAs and Smartphones), is thumbing or thumb typing. This can be accomplished using one or both thumbs. Similar to desktop keyboards and input devices, if a user overuses keys which need hard presses and/or have small and unergonomic layouts, it could cause thumb tendonitis or other repetitive strain injury. (Wikipedia)
    </text>
    <text>
        When we talk about motivating others, the justification is the end result (either we want to avoid the pain or go towards pleasure) or what we want to get the person to do. How we achieve the end result, are our alternatives. As a manager, we need to understand the other person's justification and then come up with alternatives. We may then choose the right alternative. However, in general, we choose the first or the emotionally satisfying one. Typically people stop at this level of analysis and start to act. But a good manager would think of the following also: Will the action guarantee the consequence? What about other unintended consequences? This requires a certain experience. Are we capable of doing this action? Intention and the selection of the most ideal alternative do not guarantee execution, if we do not have the skills and the experience. Most motivational tactics fail, because without execution capability, they is only wishful thinking.
    </text>
    <text>
        Two common terms used to describe a salesperson are "Farmer" and "Hunter". The reality is that most professional salespeople have a little of both. A hunter is often associated with aggressive personalities who use aggressive sales technique. In terms of sales methodology, a hunter refers to a person whose focus is on bringing in and closing deals. This process is called "sales capturing". An example is a commodity sale such as a long distance salesperson, shoe salesperson and to a degree a car salesperson. Their job is to find and convert buyers. A sales farmer is someone who creates sales demand through activities that directly influence and alter the buying process.
    </text>
    <text>
        Editing is a growing field of work in the service industry. Paid editing services may be provided by specialized editing firms or by self-employed (freelance) editors. Editing firms may employ a team of in-house editors, rely on a network of individual contractors or both. Such firms are able to handle editing in a wide range of topics and genres, depending on the skills of individual editors. The services provided by these editors may be varied and can include proofreading, copy editing, online editing, developmental editing, editing for search engine optimization (SEO), etc. Self-employed editors work directly for clients or offer their services through editing firms, or both. They may specialize in a type of editing and in a particular subject area. Those who work directly for authors and develop professional relationships with them are called authors' editors.
    </text>
    <text>
        A data entry clerk is a member of staff employed to enter or update data into a computer system. Data is often entered into a computer from paper documents using a keyboard. The keyboards used can often have special keys and multiple colors to help in the task and speed up the work. Proper ergonomics at the workstation is a common topic considered. The Data Entry Clerk may also use a mouse, and a manually-fed scanner may be involved. Speed and accuracy, not necessarily in that order, are the key measures of the job; it is possible to do this job from home.
    </text>
    <text>
        A freelancer or freelance worker, is a term commonly used for a person who is self-employed and is not necessarily committed to a particular employer long-term. Freelance workers are sometimes represented by a company or a temporary agency that resells freelance labor to clients; others work independently or use professional associations or websites to get work. While the term "independent contractor" would be used in a higher register of English to designate the tax and employment classes of this type of worker, the term freelancing is most common in culture and creative industries and this term specifically motions to participation therein. Fields, professions, and industries where freelancing is predominant include: music, writing, acting, computer programming, web design, graphic design, translating and illustrating, film and video production and other forms of piece work which some cultural theorists consider as central to the cognitive-cultural economy.
    </text>
</texts>
